So far, we've looked at ways to discretize continuous state spaces.
到目前为止 我们已经讨论了离散化连续状态空间的各种方式
This enables us to use
这些方式使我们能够几乎不做修改
existing reinforcement learning algorithms with little or no modification.
就能使用现有的强化学习算法
But there are some limitations.
但是也存在一些限制
When the underlying space is complicated,
当底层空间很复杂时
the number of discrete states needed can become very large.
所需的离散状态数量可能会很大
Thus, we lose the advantage of discretization.
因此就失去了离散化的优势
Moreover, if you think about positions in the state space that are nearby,
此外 对于状态空间里临近的位置
you would expect their values to be similar, or smoothly changing.
它们的值应该相似或者平滑地变化
Discretization doesn't always exploit this characteristic,
但是离散化并非始终会利用这一特性
failing to generalize well across the space.
无法跨空间地有效泛化
What we're after is the true state value function v pi,
我们要获得的是真实的状态值函数 vπ
or action value function q pi.
或动作值函数 qπ
Which is typically smooth and continuous over the entire space.
通常在整个空间内都比较平滑连续
As you can imagine,
可以想象
capturing this completely is practically infeasible except for some very simple problems.
除了一些非常简单的问题之外 完全捕获这种特性几乎不可行
Our best hope is function approximation.
我们的最佳希望是函数逼近
It is still an approximation because we don't know what the true underlying function is.
依然是逼近结果 因为我们不知道真正的底层函数是什么
A general way to define such an approximation is to
定义此类函数逼近的一般方法是
introduce a parameter vector W that shapes the function.
引入一个表示函数形状的参数向量 W
Our tasks then, reduces to tweaking
我们的任务变成调整这个参数向量
this parameter vector till we find the desired approximation.
直到找到理想的逼近结果
Note that the approximating function can either map a state to its value,
注意逼近函数可以将状态映射到其值
or a state action pair to the corresponding q value.
或将状态动作对映射到相应的 q 值
Another form is where we map from one state to a number of different q values,
另一种形式是从一个状态映射到一堆不同的 q 值
one for each action all at once.
同时映射到每个动作
This is especially useful for q learning as we'll see later.
这对 Q 学习来说尤其实用 稍后我们会讲解
Let's focus on this first case.
先来看看第一种情况
Approximating a state value function.
逼近状态值函数
Now, we have this box here in the middle that's supposed to do some magic.
中间的方框应该会完成处理流程
And convert the state s,
将状态 S 和参数 W
and parameter vector W into a scalar value.
转换为标量值
But how? The first thing we need to do
但是如何转换呢？
is to ensure we have a vector representing the state.
首先我们需要确保有一个表示状态的向量
Your state might already be a vector in which case you don't need to do anything.
你的状态可能已经是一个向量 这样的话 你不需要进行任何处理
In general, we'll define a transformation that converts any given state s
通常 我们将定义一个转换算法
into a feature vector X S. This also gives us more flexibility,
将任何给定状态 S 转换为特征向量 X(s) 这样也给我们带来了更多的灵活性
since we don't have to operate on the raw state values.
因为我们不需要对原始状态值进行运算
We can use any computed or derived features instead.
我们可以改为使用任何计算或推导的特征
Okay, we now have a feature vector X S,
现在我们已经有了
and a parameter vector W,
特征向量 X(s) 和参数向量 W
and we want a scalar value.
我们想要获得一个标量值
What do we do when we have two vectors,
如果我们有两个向量并想要生成标量
and want to produce a scalar?
该怎么办？
Dot Product. Yes. It's the simplest thing we could do.
进行点积运算 没错 这是最简单的方式
In fact, this is the same as computing a linear combination of features.
实际上 这和计算特征的线性组合一样
Multiply each feature with the corresponding weight, and sum it up.
将每个特征与相应的权重相乘 然后求和
This is known as linear function approximation.
称之为线性函数逼近
That is we are trying to approximate
即我们尝试使用线性函数
the underlying value function with a linear function.
逼近底层值函数